in this video we're going to look at
creating correcting entries in Dynamics
and compare that to the experience of
creating reversing entries and
correcting dimensions in business
Central to begin let's go into SL
navigate to general ledger Journal
transactions in journal transactions PV
and pull in a previously posted
transaction to
correct select correct Journal
transaction
there are three options to select
reverse the journal entry or reverse and
create a correcting entry or to just
copy the entry to make manual changes to
that entry for our purposes we'll select
the first option to only reverse the
journal
entry okay the warning message noting
the new reversal batch created now there
is an unposted reversal batch that
completely reverses the original posted
batch I can see that the system has
pulled in the account and amounts and
reversed the debits and
credits now we can post the correcting
entry by running post
transactions let's look at how we can
reverse a posted journal entry in
business
Central first I'll select the general
ledger entry window that I have pinned
to my dashboard for easy access once in
the general ledger entry window I can
search for the journal entry I want to
reverse now that I have found the
journal entry I will select to reverse
the
transaction you can see it's defaulted
in the journal entry information and I
will process the reversal once the
reverse is complete you can see it has
reversed the amount posted in the
original journal
entry finally let's say you notice a
journal entry was posted using an
incorrect Dimension and missing another
dimension you can reverse the
transaction or you can use the correct
Dimension
functionality to correct or add a
dimension value I will search for the
journal entry I want to correct here you
can see that we have posted to the area
Dimension with value 60 the entry is
also missing the business group
Dimension instead of choosing to reverse
the transaction we'll select to correct
the dimension
in the new dimension value code I'll
select the correct value for the journal
entry I will also add the missing
Dimension enter the description as to
why the change is being made now we will
run the change Dimension process once
complete we can refresh the window and
see that the correct Dimension value is
on the journal entry reversing and
correcting Dimensions is a quick and
simple process in business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources